<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | David Fernandez Bonet</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/english/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/english/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu58c89dd6a69a3034ac14e71a46441a12_1194_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/english/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>What They Don’t Tell You About Freedom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/english/post/educated_ramblings/what-they-dont-tell-you-about-freedom-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/english/post/educated_ramblings/what-they-dont-tell-you-about-freedom-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We love freedom. We love the feeling of flying through the sky, of sliding down mountains, and of exploring vast oceans. Freedom is what we see when we escape to our vacations. Freedom is a democratic ideal. Liberté, egalité, fraternité: freedom is the first word of the trilogy that fuelled the French Revolution. We love freedom so much that we constantly desire it, fight for it, and even die for it: the door that leads to a universe of possibilities. However, with possibilities come choices, and with choices comes suffering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course, suffering starts at the supermarket. As a student, you are given a simple task: survive! In order to complete this difficult task, the supermarket is there to assist you. A large supermarket can be daunting, so you decide to start easy, with milk. Once your white prey is detected, you are tempted to go and catch it… but wait! Should you buy 1%, 2% or 5% fat? Actually, should you get milk that comes from a cow? What about a plant-based alternative like almond or oat milk? Or a thicker option like a creamy filmjölk? So many choices and the supermarket adventure has only just begun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/freedom.png&#34; alt=&#34;milk_choice&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Terrifying choice - ©️ Vendela Hamberg&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rapidly growing world offers more and more options. The intuitive belief is that being presented with multiple options makes it easier to choose wisely. The more options, the more likely it is that you choose the right one. But when there are endless possibilities, choices become complicated. It is easy to buy the idea that having more possibilities is beneficial. At the end of the day, you just have to choose the best one! Nonetheless, an ocean of possibilities makes the choice extremely difficult. It can consume both your time and energy. Furthermore, the harder the choice, the more likely it is that you’ll regret it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain choices might seem unimportant, like choosing which milk to buy. Conversely, there are choices that severely shape the direction of your life. Picture the three most important people in your life. Chances are that one of these three people will experience cancer in some form or another. Chances are that one of the three most important people in your life is you, yourself. Most healthy people agree that if they had cancer, they would like to choose and customize their treatment. It makes sense, as if you carefully weigh the objective and subjective trade-offs, you will find the optimal treatment. However, almost no actual cancer patients share this perception and suddenly really do not want to decide for themselves. The decision is left entirely up to the doctor. Why is this case so different?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The harder a choice is, the more painful the decision-making. A choice can be made difficult because of its consequences, such as a cancer treatment, or due to the sheer number of possibilities and options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine being offered two cancer treatments. After consulting your doctor and doing some research yourself, you might think you’ve found the optimal treatment. Now imagine being offered not two, but ten treatments. The decision suddenly becomes a heavy burden. It feels like an ominous exam that weighs you down. Selecting the wrong treatment could potentially end you. That is why cancer patients resort to the doctor’s expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, doctors do not decide for us which milk to buy. Doctors do not decide if you should continue studying at your university. Doctors do not decide if you should be in that complicated relationship. Is it possible to deal with choices without our doctor’s assistance?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are obsessed with optimization. Especially as engineering students. We are concerned with making the best choice instead of simply making a choice that we are happy with. When there are many options available, it becomes harder to determine which is the best. This can cause a gloomy feeling of regret after making a choice. The more options, the greater the regret. Sometimes there are two options that are both extremely good, and choosing one over the other is daunting. Just like asking a mother which child is her favorite. There is no correct answer, or at least no mother would admit that there is. If forced to choose one, the feeling is bitter, sharp, and unhappy. How can we deal with such difficult decisions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter satisficing. Satisficing is a heuristic that promotes searching for available alternatives until one of them meets your expectations. In other words, satisficing is the art of deciding your expectations and sticking to them. Once those standards are met, you become satisfied and will not look for anything else. The concept was introduced in economics as an administrative strategy, but it can be applied to everyday life. For example, if you are looking for plant-based milk and see almond milk, you just grab it. The fact that you are not even considering that sexy-looking oat milk deletes regret from your decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can be extended to more meaningful aspects of life, such as career and relationships. For instance, there is no need to consider working if you are financially stable and content with studying. There are many great potential partners, but no need whatsoever to begin considering them if you are in a healthy relationship. Satisficing might appear as a kind of conformism, but satisficing is not about lowering standards. Rather, it is about deciding what they are and sticking to them. The key is to be happy with your decisions simply because they met your standards. No regrets, no looking back. No time lost examining all the possibilities. No sleepless nights wondering what might have been.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freedom is powerful, and we should continue to praise it. But we should also be careful with what we wish for because we might just get it. Managing freedom can be challenging, which is why satisficing can be very helpful. Although satisficing has been traditionally used mostly in economics and business management, it can also fit neatly into our toolbox for handling everyday life. With the right mindset, limitations on freedom can lead us to reach the greatest level of happiness within society. Freedom can in fact be fantastic, don’t forget!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So you hit the jackpot?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/english/post/educated_ramblings/so-you-have-won-the-jackpot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/english/post/educated_ramblings/so-you-have-won-the-jackpot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SO YOU HIT THE JACKPOT?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your mouth is wide open, your hands are shaking, your brain is in utter disbelief. You hear someone playing the drums, but turns out it’s your heart. Congratulations! You just won the lottery, hit the jackpot!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the Universe gave what you deserve. After all that suffering, you are rich! And not rich as in, look at my brand new car, but rich as in look at my brand new island. You cannot help but feel rewarded, blessed, and above all: like the luckiest being on the entire planet. However, feelings are feelings and reality is reality. You had luck, indeed, but snap back to reality: it was the bad kind of luck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew Jackson Whittaker Jr. was an American businessman, with a career and a construction company. As a semi-accidental result of his entrepreneurship and ambition, his company was doing more than just ok, and he was beyond financially stable, and was approaching boredom, without breaking and backing away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Experts estimated Jack’s net worth to be about 17 million US dollars before he hit the jackpot. The Powerball multi-state lottery was, at the time, the largest prize sum ever won by a single individual and a single ticket, in the history of the American lottery. Awarding him with an amount of a grand total of 315 million dollars. Mr. Whittaker was determined, or, at least he said so at the time, to continue with his life, as if nothing had changed. He hoped he would be able to spend more time with his family, while continuing to answer his own phone, open his own front door, and perhaps, if need be: turn to God for guidance. &amp;ldquo;He&amp;rsquo;s still working on me.&amp;rdquo;: was his interpretation of God&amp;rsquo;s words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when one wins such a gravitational sum? Well, Whittaker decided to donate part of his winnings to the Church and other Christian Charities, deeming 10% to be quite a generous quantity. Needless to say, the Church of God was delighted and in humble gratitude built a multi-million dollar facility for the innocent christian children. Nevertheless, Christian Altruism didn’t turn out to be his savior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wise old Whittacker frequented a local restaurant, where he was used to breaking his daily fast: breakfast, getting his daily dose of caffeine. Attracted by the aroma of caffeine in the cute cafe, other addicts arrived. The lucky winner quickly became the subject of financial stalkers, that is, mobs of people whose daughters had coincidentally acquired cancer and were in desperate need of Whittackers charitable christian values. Currency burning with clarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of them even had prepared powerful presentations, generating genius business ideas. Presenting perpetual motion machines, a feat which would insult the intellectual integrity of physics fanboys and fanatics. Others, lacking the lucrative spirit for financial finessing, bluntly begged for bars of cold cash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, Whittaker walked away from the cafe, leaving his favorite breakfast place in the past. His future found security in hired professionals: operators were ordered to sort out his mail, a couple of detectives filtered out con men and scammers. Admittedly, he really wanted to make good choices, helping people who needed him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, this is not the story of such a saint. Two weeks after the lucky day, he was seen in the Pink Pony. Far from being a harmless happy hippie place, it was a harmful horrible horrendous nightmare.. The Pink Pony strip club caters to slithering snakes like white man Whittaker. Throwing thousands of dollars on the counter, claiming that he was there to “whoop it up”, Whittaker began dishing out demands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The manager of the club suggested that he re-pocket his wads of cash, stating that the strip club serves up serious struggle for those asking for trouble. Equity in that environment is equivalent to toying with trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although he escaped assault that night, he most definitely drank himself to hell and returned, heading home in a lottery winner’s taxi, that is, a luxurious limousine. Thereafter, things really started to go severely south.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Losing money may be sad, but being betrayed by so-called friends is heart-breaking. But there is something worse than betrayal, something that cannot be repaired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whittaker’s car was twice broken into, the culprits were not unknown criminals, but trusted acquaintances. These life-long “friends” had observed Whittaker’s routines and machine learned that large quantities of cash were kept in the car. The first time, prescription drugs were put in his drink. The second, they intimidated Whittaker’s granddaughter, insinuating insults to her person for information. Their methods resulted in a total of $700,000 stolen dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brandi, Whittaker’s granddaughter, was not only pressured to produce information. Worse than that, her loving grandfather gave her large amounts of money. This attracted certain people, and the filtering mechanisms of young teenager Brandi were not well established. Her fickle firewalls fell down, and she did not fare well, and had to say her farewells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She dropped out of high school, drove around exploiting expensive cars, eating junk food as if she were trying to reach a sumo wrestler&amp;rsquo;s weight. It was not long until drugs began to appear in the equation. Such drugs were not limited to cannabis and alcohol alone. Brandi Whittaker started taking white powders. The crack cracked her open, exposing its extremely addictive properties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Brandi was not exactly poor and upon family suggestion, she agreed to go to rehab. Twice. Unfortunately, addiction remained her affliction. Following her pathetic path like a parasite, her boyfriend, Jimmy jimmied along: eventually dropping dead of an overdone dose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grounded by guilt, as it was her money that enabled the deadly drugs that killed her boyfriend. Three months later, Brandi was buried, along with her name. Although the cause seemed to be an overdose, Whittaker suspected foul play. The apple of Whittaker’s eye was dead and gone. Unable to avoid ruminating over the root cause, the seeds of supposed success, lended by the lottery winnings, his sanity suffered and withered with Brandi’s demise, dirt on his sad soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whittaker’s case is not isolated. Billie Bob Harrel committed suicide after endless requests for money from friends and family. Evelyn Adams declared bankruptcy after gambling away her fortune. Thomas Strong died during a quarrel with the police, coming straight from the underground. Jeffrey Dampier was kidnapped and murdered by his own sister-in-law, inlaws becoming lawless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homicide, drug overdoses, kidnappings, and bankruptcy are normally not logically linked with the lure of the lottery. Nonetheless, and needless to note, troublesome tragedies attributes allocated, allotted by the lottery. Therefore, if you are ever lucky enough to lose the lottery, you might be interested in the intricate instructions to avoid the loss of heaven and pain of hell: the undesirable brutality brought by bankruptcy, demonizing, dehumanizing, delegating death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is to remain calm. Not because your yoga teacher says so, or because your meditation app mandates it, but because you must translate the trainwreck of thunder and thoughts. Above all, rise above boasting, blast your bitterness, be better. No need to say nothing, no fala nada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before declaring yourself the winner, you contact and confirm, acquire the affirmation of an attorney. Accept ayuda, protection from potential peleas, build barries for battles you might be faced with and forced to fight. Extra points for an attorney, independent of incentives, already introduced and used to incriminating criminals, well versed in dancing with wealthy willpower.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second step is to decide how much you are going to give away, and don’t give away your integrity. Give money to family and friends, christians, children, and charity. Set up a favorable foundation. But again, be brave, be bold, be cunningly consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are going to ask you for money no matter what, and deciding beforehand how much to give will clear uncertainties not only for yourself, but also for potential perpetual-motion machine inventors, pitching and bitching. It can also deal with family quarrels about who gets what. Decades of Christian Christmas dinners and manipulative Monopoly games have proven that you definitely want to avoid family quarrels, so trust your experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third step is to hire a financial advisor and establish a safety net for your inner circle. So to sum up, if you ever become a lottery loser, which is a BIG IF IN ALL CAPS, don’t panic, or at least keep the panic organic, and get help. Professionals are pertinent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buying a lottery ticket is not an advisable financial move, as the estimated return is lower than the investment. Not quite like the riveting rocket science scene. However, it is safe, not surprising, to acknowledge the real reason why one should abstain from buying lottery tickets. Not because of the low likelihood of winning, but because of the dangers and delusions it demands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reasonable point in favor of lottery spending $ is that it gives hope, and, in a way, you are buying a pleasant state of mind. You are buying the chance of a magic trick that will ease worries, solve problems, and take you into a world beyond your wildest dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as Whittaker’s example shows, dreams can easily become memes, or nightmares. It is easy to think that you can do better than those who failed before you, see US politics. And maybe you are right, but do not be a fool, keep it cool. It will not be an easy path of least resistance. If you hit the jackpot, it’ll hit you back, and if you mistake your heartbeat for the sound of drums in Rio, go see a doctor. And a lawyer. And a financial advisor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/lottery.png&#34; alt=&#34;Lottery&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;©️ Carl Housten&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The need for leaders</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/english/post/educated_ramblings/the-need-for-leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/english/post/educated_ramblings/the-need-for-leaders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Irresistibly, you get lost in wonder, for the starry night could not be more charming. Shining stars are scattered in the sky like prominent figures are scattered in history. Great thinkers, creative artists, bold leaders. Leaders like Cleopatra, who ruled Egypt and influenced Roman politics like no other. Leaders like Napoleon, whose military brilliance was feared by many, and made France the dominant European power. Leaders like Jesus, who long after dead has more followers than any influencer could ever dream of. It seems like great people are necessary to achieve great feats. But is it so? Do we really need leaders?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/leaders2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Leaders2&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;©️ Karolina Shi&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The animal kingdom has a strong opinion on this topic. From the smallest ant to the biggest elephant, social animals have hierarchies that define their lifestyle. For example, a typical ant colony is structured into workers, warriors and the queen and its mating partners. However, is it a good idea to compare human society to the animal kingdom? The ant colony structure sounds oddly familiar. It is curiously described using words like queen and warrior, which will surely remind the reader of human medieval hierarchy. Rest assured, the royalty had no such things as “mating partners”. A sophisticated word was used instead, the nobility. The previous comparison shows that it is important to remember that we are nothing but animals. Furthermore, social animals by nature, as Aristotle once said. While it is true that humanity can develop a highly complex social structure, its complexness should not distract us from the fact that it is hierarchical. Just like regular social animals. This recurrent pattern in nature supports the statement that leaders are necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But necessary for what? Survival, if our observations are purely based in nature. Nonetheless, when survival is already assured, leadership can accomplish more. For instance, the pyramids, landing on the moon or finding the Covid-19 vaccine are examples of how cooperation enabled great feats. And such cooperation would not be possible without leaders. It seems like the bigger the project, the greater the necessity for structure, cooperation and leadership. In fact, the so-called Dunbar&amp;rsquo;s number suggests how many social relationships humans can have. Far from being a specific number, it simply shows that human beings are socially limited. In other words, a thousand Facebook friends are not a thousand real friends. However, humans seem to ignore such a limit when it comes to society building. Dunbar’s number can easily be surpassed by a small city, not to mention an entire country. But is this cooperation between humans achieved by the means of leadership?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Universal Declaration of Human Rights rests among the pillars of dignity, liberty and equality. As it turns out, equality is a fundamental value in our society that ought to guide our moral compass and influence our decisions. Because of it, horizontal organizational structures (HOS) seem to be desirable and leaders unnecessary. HOS are structures with no clear leader, where everyone holds a similar rank and can make their own decisions. In short, where everyone is equal. It sounds like a utopia to reach, a dream that one must pursue. But I wonder if the reason why it sounds like a dream is that it is too good to be true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is time to wake up and feel the tough ground of reality. We are not equal. Everyone is different. Character traits, skills, personal views, experiences. Each of them makes us who we are and in many ways, makes us unique. HOS are an interesting concept, but they are not widespread across the globe because they do not work. Our differences are the underlying reason why we need social structure. Take, for example, children and their parents. It is not hard to imagine how a HOS structure would go wrong in this scenario. Because parents are fully developed adults and have years of experience, they will make good leaders for a three-year-old. However, the opposite case is likely to result in food poisoning due to candy consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The parents’ example is not isolated. There are plenty of times when the skilful and charismatic will have an easier time when trying to achieve ambitious goals that require cooperation. There are born leaders like Cleopatra, Jesus or Napoleon. Still, if Napoleon was asked to cook an excellent Christmas dinner, he would not be a fit leader, as his military prowess would only prove useful to stab the turkey. As such, leaders are ever-changing and are entirely dependent on the task at hand. Consequently, a leader is not an individual in itself, it is a role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, social hierarchies are found all over the animal kingdom and human beings are not an exception. Leaders are necessary for survival, but when survival is secured, leaders enable greater feats. Although equality is a desirable ideal, it often fails to work when applied to organizational structures. HOS are not widespread because our uniqueness requires leadership. Finally, leaders are not to be confused with individuals, as a leader is a role that can change depending on the goal to achieve. Next time you raise your sight into a dark night, remember that the sky would not be the sky without its stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/leaders1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Leaders1&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;©️ Karolina Shi&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The price of health</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/english/post/educated_ramblings/the-price-of-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/english/post/educated_ramblings/the-price-of-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What a beautiful day. The sun is shining, the sky is clear and you feel ready. It is time to grab that good old bike. The plan? Cycle until your thoughts get lost and your body gets numb. It has been a while since you last enjoyed the pleasure of exercise and quietness. Suddenly, you hear a Formula 1 sound and see an athletic cycler shouting at you from behind. Next thing you know, you are wounded and on the floor. Was that a bike or a spacecraft from NASA? It had to be a rocket, otherwise the passenger would not be dressed like an astronaut. He comes to your aid, and you confirm that yes indeed, he does look like a spaceman. From top to bottom, there is no single part of his body that is not covered by a piece of cycling equipment. Aerodynamic helmet, cycler goggles, futuristic watch… the list could go on and on. After the little accident, you decide to go home and heal your wounds. For once, electric scooters are not to blame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But who is to blame? Why are there cyclists equipped to do the Tour de France when in reality they are doing the Tour de Solna? Why are sugar-based pills being taken as an all-in-one cure? Why are diet books being sold today at the same rate as toilet paper was in March 2020? These apparently unrelated scenarios have a common denominator: we decided to pay for our health.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And by decided, of course, I mean pushed. Companies are constantly pushing us to buy products. To do so, they create necessities out of nowhere. This is just an intermediate step in the beautiful drama called “The money in your pocket is now the money in my pocket”. We are told that we need vitamin supplements to be healthy. Every day, our hair needs to be cleansed from all the oils that our skin produces naturally. The wrinkles that reveal our age must be hidden, or even better, erased… And of course, the only way to achieve it is none other than money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/health2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;health2&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;©️ Victoria Rohrer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an old tale that rings a bell or two. But it is especially outrageous when we are told that our health is a pay-to-win game. It is easy to exploit fears and insecurities, and the wellness industry thrives on those. According to research by the Global Wellness Institute, the wellness industry is valued at $4.5 trillion and is continuing to grow at a historic rate [1]. From an investor point of view, wellness pays off. The industry’s expansion is clear: wellness tourism, wellness apps, wellness at the workplace… these concepts are growing and becoming popular [2] [3]. But is it necessary to go to India to find peace, is health something to be downloaded, is yoga the solution to stressful working environments?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dark side of the wellness industry is born when insecurity exploits are combined with unreasonable expectations of “becoming your better self”. Wellness has become synonymous with productivity and self-optimization. The idea that you can buy an improved version of yourself is, simply put, attractive. The fast, easy path. But wellness isn’t something that can be consumed. My concern with this path is not only that it can be a scam, but that it poses a threat to the consumer’s mental health [4]. What happens when you fail to fulfil expectations? When you realize you are not a fit cycler despite all the protein shakes, when you realize you are still bald despite the caffeine shampoo, when you realize that despite the expensive meditation retreat… you still have cancer? It surely must not be what you bought, people on the ad told nothing but success stories! It has to be faced, you are the problem. And that “problem” is now crying and trying to figure out what went wrong. Ironically, the wellness industry is disrupting wellness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A substantial amount of the wellness industry products are simply not proven to work. Scientifically, that is. For example, homeopathy, vitamins and hair-loss treatments often fall into this category [5] [6] [7]. Having vitamins for breakfast will not make you feel better, but will make your pee tremendously valuable! The problem: it can be as difficult to prove that the product works as it can be to prove that it does &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; work. Unsurprisingly, it took a while to prove that smoking caused lung cancer. This is because correlation does not imply causation and because companies have moneyed interests. Science, rigorous science, is painfully slow. Marketing, however, is stupidly fast. “I am doing the new carnivore diet. Still stuck with Keto diet? That’s so 2017!”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health might be difficult to come by in certain situations. Being aware of your insecurities and fears is key to avoid falling victim to the wellness industry. Chances are that spending money on a miraculous pill or a trendy diet book will not solve any serious problem. Good sleep, a diverse diet and an active social and physical life are your best bets at staying healthy. It is okay to be afraid of ageing or cancer. It is also okay to accept them when they come. What really matters is to spend effort instead of money, to go to the doctor instead of the beauty salon. And if you wake up and decide to enjoy the sunny day as an alternative to the Tour de Solna&amp;hellip; you might catch yourself thinking, what a beautiful day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/health1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;health1&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;©️ Victoria Rohrer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The what and the how</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/english/post/educated_ramblings/the-what-and-the-how/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/english/post/educated_ramblings/the-what-and-the-how/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The what and the how&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was a child, I did not care about &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; I looked to others. I would not mind a stained T-shirt, messy hair, or a chaotic room. To my mother’s despair, I simply was like that. And it would be foolish to say that this belief is completely gone. The belief came from watching &lt;em&gt;Beauty and the Beast&lt;/em&gt; countless times. As a consequence, ‘beauty is found within’ resonated with me and my distaste for spotless appearances was born. Because I watched the movie so many times, by sheer exposure, its message became an unalterable truth to me. But this is no longer. As the years went by, it became clear not only that appearances are important but that the &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; is as relevant as the &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt;. Or even more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is undeniable that &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; we are, matters. Maybe kind, or faithful, or an space exploration enthusiast. It matters. &lt;em&gt;How&lt;/em&gt; we present ourselves to the world, however, does matter as well. For example, we would pay attention to a lab-coated physicist talking about life possibilities in Mars. But we would not listen to a tin-foil hatted lunatic claiming that Martians are coming for him. In that situation, the willingness to listen is substituted by the urge to run, isn’t it? Both are talking about life forms on Mars, but the context has drastically changed. The &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; has drastically changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why, maybe the tin-foil hatted man is telling the truth! Because it is difficult to have a perfect assessment of something, millions of years of natural selection have casted a curse on us: judgements. Judgements, even if biased, must be done to ensure survival. And this is what we do: survive and judge. Judging was in our ancestors, it is in ourselves and it will be in our descendance. The beauty in this apparently inescapable curse is that it can be used to our advantage. How? The answer lies in rationality. All prejudices vanish and judgements become a helpful tool through rationality. A tool that we may use to discern whether the lunatic is, indeed, a lunatic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;, of course, is not restricted to external appearances only. What we say and what we do are of importance, but how we say it and how we do it is even more important. To illustrate this point, a citation from an episode of the podcast “The Anthropocene Reviewed” will be useful. In this podcast, John Green reviews a facet of the human era on a five-star scale. In this case, sunsets -which are the &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt;- are being reviewed using a deep and meaningful &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“And then he would do something absolutely extraordinary (&lt;em&gt;referring to his one year old puppy&lt;/em&gt;)—he would roll over onto his back, and present his soft belly. I always marvelled at the courage of that, his ability to be so absolutely vulnerable to us, to offer us the place that ribs don’t protect, and trust that we weren’t going to bite or stab him. It’s hard to trust the world like that, to show it your belly. […] maybe I’m just scared that if I show the world my belly, it will devour me. And so I wear the armor of cynicism, and hide behind the great walls of irony, and only glimpse beauty with my back turned to it, through the Claude Glass. […] And so I try to turn toward that scattered light, belly out, and I tell myself: This doesn’t look like a picture. And it doesn’t look like a God. It is a sunset, and it is wildly beautiful, and this whole thing you’ve been doing where almost nothing gets five stars because almost nothing is perfect? That’s b.s. So much is perfect. Starting with this.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt;, the sunset, is elevated to a whole new level by means of a beautiful &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;. One could describe the sunset and its colours, one could explain all the phenomena that simultaneously go on, one could look at the sun and just open the mouth in awe. However, John Green talks about his dog. He masterfully turns the loyal animal into a mirror that reflects human vulnerability, and the heavy burden that we must carry when protecting it. Protection that is no longer necessary while experiencing the sunset. An ideal instant, perfection. Five stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, special attention must be put in the &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt;. It affects the &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; in an impactful manner, sometimes wholly turning around situations. This can be applied in appearances, but also in the language used or the actions taken. No matter how bright the &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; is, the &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; should never be eclipsed by it. I can now understand my poor mother trying to brush the hair of a hopeless child. Because yes, beauty is found within. But one should never forget to look outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/ellen_b%c3%a4ck_what_how.png&#34; alt=&#34;Fountain of Youth&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sunset - ©️ Ellen Bäck&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Figure Shortcode</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/english/post/figure-shortcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 21:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/english/post/figure-shortcode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hugo has &lt;code&gt;figure&lt;/code&gt; shortcode built-in, so you can easily add figure captions or hyperlink rel attributes to images. Documentations can be found here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/shortcodes/#figure&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://gohugo.io/content-management/shortcodes/#figure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This theme has 3 CSS classes made for figure elements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;big&lt;/code&gt;: images will break the width limit of main content area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;left&lt;/code&gt;: images will float to the left.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;right&lt;/code&gt;: images will float to the right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a figure has no class set, the image will behave just like a normal markdown image: &lt;code&gt;![]()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples; please be aware that these styles only take effect when the page width is over 1300px.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-normal-without-any-classes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://via.placeholder.com/1600x800&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      figure-normal (without any classes)
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pellentesque posuere sem nec nunc varius, id hendrerit arcu consequat. Maecenas commodo, sapien ut gravida porttitor, dolor risus facilisis enim, eget pharetra nibh nisl porttitor sapien. Proin finibus elementum ligula sit amet hendrerit. Praesent et erat sodales ante accumsan pharetra non eu nulla. Sed vehicula consequat lorem, a fermentum ante faucibus quis. Aliquam erat volutpat. In vitae tincidunt dui. Proin sit amet ligula sodales, elementum tortor et, venenatis sem. Maecenas non nisl erat. Curabitur nec velit eros. Ut cursus lacus nisi, non pretium libero euismod et. Fusce luctus in nisi quis sollicitudin. Aenean nec blandit ligula. Duis ac felis lorem. Proin tellus tellus, dictum nec tempus sit amet, venenatis ac felis. Sed in pharetra nulla, non mollis sem.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure class=&#34;big&#34; id=&#34;figure-figure-big&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://via.placeholder.com/1600x800&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      figure-big
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donec nec tincidunt est. Sed id metus in erat fringilla mattis at id turpis. Aliquam tempor vehicula faucibus. Phasellus consequat aliquam odio. Morbi a ex vitae sapien porta auctor. Orci varius natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Donec sit amet nulla arcu. Praesent ut tortor purus. Praesent id eros diam. Pellentesque vitae dolor at nibh ultrices accumsan eu id urna. Aliquam finibus interdum orci in varius. Pellentesque a enim condimentum, condimentum felis id, vehicula augue. Vivamus cursus commodo eros nec lacinia.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure class=&#34;medium&#34; id=&#34;figure-figure-medium&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://via.placeholder.com/1600x800&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      figure-medium
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a libero varius, luctus ligula et, bibendum tortor. Sed sit amet dui malesuada, mattis justo id, ultricies enim. Vestibulum ante ipsum primis in faucibus orci luctus et ultrices posuere cubilia Curae; Aliquam sollicitudin cursus feugiat. Vivamus suscipit ipsum eget lobortis sollicitudin. Fusce vehicula neque tellus. Integer eu posuere quam, id laoreet tortor. Mauris sit amet turpis urna. Donec venenatis tempor dolor, nec laoreet orci aliquet et. Sed condimentum elit eu tristique aliquam. Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Nunc luctus ipsum sit amet nisl maximus pellentesque.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure class=&#34;small&#34; id=&#34;figure-figure-small&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://via.placeholder.com/1600x800&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      figure-small
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pellentesque posuere sem nec nunc varius, id hendrerit arcu consequat. Maecenas commodo, sapien ut gravida porttitor, dolor risus facilisis enim, eget pharetra nibh nisl porttitor sapien. Proin finibus elementum ligula sit amet hendrerit. Praesent et erat sodales ante accumsan pharetra non eu nulla. Sed vehicula consequat lorem, a fermentum ante faucibus quis. Aliquam erat volutpat. In vitae tincidunt dui. Proin sit amet ligula sodales, elementum tortor et, venenatis sem. Maecenas non nisl erat. Curabitur nec velit eros. Ut cursus lacus nisi, non pretium libero euismod et. Fusce luctus in nisi quis sollicitudin. Aenean nec blandit ligula. Duis ac felis lorem. Proin tellus tellus, dictum nec tempus sit amet, venenatis ac felis. Sed in pharetra nulla, non mollis sem.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure class=&#34;tiny&#34; id=&#34;figure-figure-tiny&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://via.placeholder.com/1600x800&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      figure-tiny
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suspendisse fringilla malesuada massa, in malesuada orci lacinia a. Praesent dapibus faucibus nisl, id volutpat elit bibendum eu. Nulla vitae laoreet nibh, eu hendrerit lacus. Donec lacinia auctor ligula, vel interdum ipsum malesuada vitae. Donec placerat a justo eu gravida. Aenean ultricies imperdiet convallis. Pellentesque accumsan non ex sed euismod. Proin bibendum lectus nec enim faucibus feugiat. Donec hendrerit nisi viverra ornare luctus. Nullam non viverra nisl. Nam vel tellus et tortor elementum volutpat sit amet et erat. Aliquam a libero quis libero porta consectetur. Etiam aliquam felis vel nulla mattis finibus. Mauris laoreet lacus arcu, sed rhoncus odio condimentum sed. Aenean in dui rutrum elit faucibus faucibus nec fringilla augue. Fusce non ornare mauris.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure class=&#34;left&#34; id=&#34;figure-figure-left&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://via.placeholder.com/400x280&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      figure-left
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a libero varius, luctus ligula et, bibendum tortor. Sed sit amet dui malesuada, mattis justo id, ultricies enim. Vestibulum ante ipsum primis in faucibus orci luctus et ultrices posuere cubilia Curae; Aliquam sollicitudin cursus feugiat. Vivamus suscipit ipsum eget lobortis sollicitudin. Fusce vehicula neque tellus. Integer eu posuere quam, id laoreet tortor. Mauris sit amet turpis urna. Donec venenatis tempor dolor, nec laoreet orci aliquet et. Sed condimentum elit eu tristique aliquam. Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Nunc luctus ipsum sit amet nisl maximus pellentesque.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure class=&#34;right&#34; id=&#34;figure-figure-right&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://via.placeholder.com/400x280&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      figure-right
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pellentesque eu consequat nunc. Vivamus eu eros ut nulla dapibus molestie in id tortor. Cras viverra ligula erat, tincidunt hendrerit diam blandit nec. Cras id urna vel dolor dictum mattis. Vestibulum congue erat ac eros molestie accumsan. Maecenas lorem nibh, maximus vel justo eget, facilisis egestas lectus. Mauris eu est ut odio blandit consequat id feugiat eros. Fusce id suscipit mi, et lacinia lectus. Mauris a arcu placerat dolor iaculis feugiat nec non mi. Ut porttitor elit tortor, eget tempus velit mollis eu. Aliquam sem nulla, dictum cursus mauris ac, semper ullamcorper leo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donec nec tincidunt est. Sed id metus in erat fringilla mattis at id turpis. Aliquam tempor vehicula faucibus. Phasellus consequat aliquam odio. Morbi a ex vitae sapien porta auctor. Orci varius natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Donec sit amet nulla arcu. Praesent ut tortor purus. Praesent id eros diam. Pellentesque vitae dolor at nibh ultrices accumsan eu id urna. Aliquam finibus interdum orci in varius. Pellentesque a enim condimentum, condimentum felis id, vehicula augue. Vivamus cursus commodo eros nec lacinia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Figure Shortcode</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/english/post/journal_reviews/figure-shortcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 21:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/english/post/journal_reviews/figure-shortcode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hugo has &lt;code&gt;figure&lt;/code&gt; shortcode built-in, so you can easily add figure captions or hyperlink rel attributes to images. Documentations can be found here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/shortcodes/#figure&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://gohugo.io/content-management/shortcodes/#figure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This theme has 3 CSS classes made for figure elements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;big&lt;/code&gt;: images will break the width limit of main content area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;left&lt;/code&gt;: images will float to the left.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;right&lt;/code&gt;: images will float to the right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a figure has no class set, the image will behave just like a normal markdown image: &lt;code&gt;![]()&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples; please be aware that these styles only take effect when the page width is over 1300px.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-normal-without-any-classes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://via.placeholder.com/1600x800&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      figure-normal (without any classes)
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pellentesque posuere sem nec nunc varius, id hendrerit arcu consequat. Maecenas commodo, sapien ut gravida porttitor, dolor risus facilisis enim, eget pharetra nibh nisl porttitor sapien. Proin finibus elementum ligula sit amet hendrerit. Praesent et erat sodales ante accumsan pharetra non eu nulla. Sed vehicula consequat lorem, a fermentum ante faucibus quis. Aliquam erat volutpat. In vitae tincidunt dui. Proin sit amet ligula sodales, elementum tortor et, venenatis sem. Maecenas non nisl erat. Curabitur nec velit eros. Ut cursus lacus nisi, non pretium libero euismod et. Fusce luctus in nisi quis sollicitudin. Aenean nec blandit ligula. Duis ac felis lorem. Proin tellus tellus, dictum nec tempus sit amet, venenatis ac felis. Sed in pharetra nulla, non mollis sem.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure class=&#34;big&#34; id=&#34;figure-figure-big&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://via.placeholder.com/1600x800&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      figure-big
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donec nec tincidunt est. Sed id metus in erat fringilla mattis at id turpis. Aliquam tempor vehicula faucibus. Phasellus consequat aliquam odio. Morbi a ex vitae sapien porta auctor. Orci varius natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Donec sit amet nulla arcu. Praesent ut tortor purus. Praesent id eros diam. Pellentesque vitae dolor at nibh ultrices accumsan eu id urna. Aliquam finibus interdum orci in varius. Pellentesque a enim condimentum, condimentum felis id, vehicula augue. Vivamus cursus commodo eros nec lacinia.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure class=&#34;medium&#34; id=&#34;figure-figure-medium&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://via.placeholder.com/1600x800&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      figure-medium
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a libero varius, luctus ligula et, bibendum tortor. Sed sit amet dui malesuada, mattis justo id, ultricies enim. Vestibulum ante ipsum primis in faucibus orci luctus et ultrices posuere cubilia Curae; Aliquam sollicitudin cursus feugiat. Vivamus suscipit ipsum eget lobortis sollicitudin. Fusce vehicula neque tellus. Integer eu posuere quam, id laoreet tortor. Mauris sit amet turpis urna. Donec venenatis tempor dolor, nec laoreet orci aliquet et. Sed condimentum elit eu tristique aliquam. Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Nunc luctus ipsum sit amet nisl maximus pellentesque.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure class=&#34;small&#34; id=&#34;figure-figure-small&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://via.placeholder.com/1600x800&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      figure-small
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pellentesque posuere sem nec nunc varius, id hendrerit arcu consequat. Maecenas commodo, sapien ut gravida porttitor, dolor risus facilisis enim, eget pharetra nibh nisl porttitor sapien. Proin finibus elementum ligula sit amet hendrerit. Praesent et erat sodales ante accumsan pharetra non eu nulla. Sed vehicula consequat lorem, a fermentum ante faucibus quis. Aliquam erat volutpat. In vitae tincidunt dui. Proin sit amet ligula sodales, elementum tortor et, venenatis sem. Maecenas non nisl erat. Curabitur nec velit eros. Ut cursus lacus nisi, non pretium libero euismod et. Fusce luctus in nisi quis sollicitudin. Aenean nec blandit ligula. Duis ac felis lorem. Proin tellus tellus, dictum nec tempus sit amet, venenatis ac felis. Sed in pharetra nulla, non mollis sem.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure class=&#34;tiny&#34; id=&#34;figure-figure-tiny&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://via.placeholder.com/1600x800&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      figure-tiny
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suspendisse fringilla malesuada massa, in malesuada orci lacinia a. Praesent dapibus faucibus nisl, id volutpat elit bibendum eu. Nulla vitae laoreet nibh, eu hendrerit lacus. Donec lacinia auctor ligula, vel interdum ipsum malesuada vitae. Donec placerat a justo eu gravida. Aenean ultricies imperdiet convallis. Pellentesque accumsan non ex sed euismod. Proin bibendum lectus nec enim faucibus feugiat. Donec hendrerit nisi viverra ornare luctus. Nullam non viverra nisl. Nam vel tellus et tortor elementum volutpat sit amet et erat. Aliquam a libero quis libero porta consectetur. Etiam aliquam felis vel nulla mattis finibus. Mauris laoreet lacus arcu, sed rhoncus odio condimentum sed. Aenean in dui rutrum elit faucibus faucibus nec fringilla augue. Fusce non ornare mauris.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure class=&#34;left&#34; id=&#34;figure-figure-left&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://via.placeholder.com/400x280&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      figure-left
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a libero varius, luctus ligula et, bibendum tortor. Sed sit amet dui malesuada, mattis justo id, ultricies enim. Vestibulum ante ipsum primis in faucibus orci luctus et ultrices posuere cubilia Curae; Aliquam sollicitudin cursus feugiat. Vivamus suscipit ipsum eget lobortis sollicitudin. Fusce vehicula neque tellus. Integer eu posuere quam, id laoreet tortor. Mauris sit amet turpis urna. Donec venenatis tempor dolor, nec laoreet orci aliquet et. Sed condimentum elit eu tristique aliquam. Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas. Nunc luctus ipsum sit amet nisl maximus pellentesque.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure class=&#34;right&#34; id=&#34;figure-figure-right&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://via.placeholder.com/400x280&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      figure-right
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pellentesque eu consequat nunc. Vivamus eu eros ut nulla dapibus molestie in id tortor. Cras viverra ligula erat, tincidunt hendrerit diam blandit nec. Cras id urna vel dolor dictum mattis. Vestibulum congue erat ac eros molestie accumsan. Maecenas lorem nibh, maximus vel justo eget, facilisis egestas lectus. Mauris eu est ut odio blandit consequat id feugiat eros. Fusce id suscipit mi, et lacinia lectus. Mauris a arcu placerat dolor iaculis feugiat nec non mi. Ut porttitor elit tortor, eget tempus velit mollis eu. Aliquam sem nulla, dictum cursus mauris ac, semper ullamcorper leo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donec nec tincidunt est. Sed id metus in erat fringilla mattis at id turpis. Aliquam tempor vehicula faucibus. Phasellus consequat aliquam odio. Morbi a ex vitae sapien porta auctor. Orci varius natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Donec sit amet nulla arcu. Praesent ut tortor purus. Praesent id eros diam. Pellentesque vitae dolor at nibh ultrices accumsan eu id urna. Aliquam finibus interdum orci in varius. Pellentesque a enim condimentum, condimentum felis id, vehicula augue. Vivamus cursus commodo eros nec lacinia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why are there males and females?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/english/post/educated_ramblings/males-and-females.-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/english/post/educated_ramblings/males-and-females.-why/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is Friday night: a nice bar, no work to do and not a single worry in your head. Until &lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt; guy comes. By the way he looks, smells, and walks, there is no doubt; he is as stoned as he will ever be. Two things are inevitable: his stupid question and your sighing. “Man, man. Why are there males and females? You know, why two sexes and not one… or three?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, you are smart enough to quickly change the topic and proceed to have a great time. However, when finally home and trying to sleep&amp;hellip; it is not possible to get the thing out of your head. We simply accepted that some animals are called male, and others female, without asking what those words really meant. But what is the essence of maleness? What, at bottom, defines a female?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We as mammals have no doubt: possession of a penis, bearing of the young, certain chromosomal features and so on are characteristics that define our sex. These criteria are well and all until you realise that it does not work in general. You will never hear: “Oh, look at these oak’s enormous breasts, it must be a female!”. As a matter of fact, there is only one fundamental feature of the sexes that can be used to label males as males, and females as females, throughout animals and plants. The so-called ‘gametes’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gametes are sex cells. Male gametes are much smaller and numerous than females’. This is true no matter the context, and it defines sex at a fundamental level. The difference is especially pronounced in reptiles and in birds, where a single egg cell is big enough and nutritious enough to feed a developing baby for several weeks. Even in humans, where the egg is microscopic, it is still many times larger than the sperm. Still, I suspect that our stoned friend would not be satisfied with a simple definition. How did this come to be, why are there even males and females?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/roisin_males_females_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Fountain of Youth&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt; ©️ Roisin Callaghan&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer that question, we have to assume a world without sex distinction, a world of isogametes (all gametes would be identical). If this scenario is unstable, meaning that it naturally evolves to a scenario with sex distinction, then we will have found a reason for males and females to exist. When two isogametes fuse, both contribute equal numbers of genes to the new individual, and they also contribute equal amounts of food reserves. Conversely, even though sperms and eggs contribute equal numbers of genes, eggs contribute far more in the way of food reserves, and this difference is key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The isogametes world is unavoidably unstable. Errors when replicating gametes do exist, and consequently there will be gametes slightly different than others. In some respects a big isogamete will have an advantage over an average-sized one, because its embryo would get a larger food supply. Therefore, there might be a trend towards bigger gametes. But there is a catch! This trend is open to exploitation. Individuals who produce smaller than average gametes can cash in when fusing with these big gametes. Without investing too much in gametes production, they get the extra-food benefits. Natural selection will favour the production of sex cells that are small and that actively seek out big ones to fuse with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we can think of two divergent sexual &amp;lsquo;strategies&amp;rsquo; evolving. There is a large-investment or &amp;lsquo;direct&amp;rsquo; strategy. This automatically opens the way for a small investment exploitative strategy. Once the divergence between the two strategies starts, it continues in a runaway fashion. Medium-sized intermediates would have been penalized, because they did not enjoy the advantages of either of the two more extreme strategies and would eventually have disappeared. And just like this, the concept of male and female comes to make sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, because the world is not perfect, there are replication errors. Because the world is not fair, a direct strategy (females) will always go with an exploitative strategy (males). So next time your stoned friend comes to you in search of deep and meaningful answers, you can 1) explain the origins of sex distinction or 2) change the topic and proceed to have fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/roisin_males_females_1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Fountain of Youth&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt; ©️ Roisin Callaghan&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fountain of Youth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/english/post/educated_ramblings/the-fountain-of-youth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/english/post/educated_ramblings/the-fountain-of-youth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine you are fooling around with Google Earth, exploring Area 51 and whatnot. However, there is a disappointing absence of alien life. Completely upset, you decide to set a new goal in search of suspicious activity. After trying out the Bermuda Triangle and Atlantis with no success, it is the Fountain of Youth’s turn. But wait, where is it supposed to be? Wouldn’t it be sensible to seek places where people live long? Immersed in this very same quest was the American National Geographic Fellow Dan Buettner. He did his research, grabbed an Earth globe and circled the places that were known for its unusual longevity, using a blue crayon. In a sudden burst of inspiration, he brilliantly named those regions “Blue Zones”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granted, there is a tiny possibility that Blue Zones do not contain the Fountain of Youth. For the love of God, maybe miraculous waters are not real. What is, indeed, real is that people residing in such zones live much longer than the average human being. We shall begin a more down-to-earth quest trying to find out why!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Icaria (Greece):&lt;/strong&gt; Icaria is an island in Greece where people eat a Mediterranean diet rich in olive oil, red wine and homegrown vegetables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ogliastra, Sardinia (Italy):&lt;/strong&gt; The Ogliastra region of Sardinia is home to some of the oldest men in the world. They live in mountainous regions where they typically work on farms and drink red wine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Okinawa (Japan):&lt;/strong&gt; Okinawa is home to the world’s oldest women, who eat soy-based foods and practice tai chi, a meditative form of exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nicoya Peninsula (Costa Rica):&lt;/strong&gt; The Nicoyan diet is based around beans and corn tortillas. The people of this area regularly perform physical jobs into old age and have a sense of life purpose known as “plan de vida.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Seventh-day Adventists in Loma Linda, California (USA):&lt;/strong&gt; The Seventh-day Adventists are religious people who believe in the second coming (advent) of Jesus Christ. They’re strict vegetarians and live in tight-knit communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because these are small regions with no connection between each other, one could easily argue that the reason for their extended longevity is purely genetic. The whims of heredity and natural selection would be to blame and we would go to sleep grimly thinking of that uncle who passed away early, fearing that it may happen to us. Luckily enough, this is not the case. Detailed studies show that genetics probably account from 20% to about 30% of longevity, marking environmental influences as the main contributing factor. If sounding smart is a priority to you, please do call it epigenetics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To no-one’s surprise, diet and lifestyle play a huge role in determining a human lifespan. So even though your grandmother is a hundred years old, your diet consisting of kex choklad and 3 daily kanelbullar may not be a good idea. Even during exam weeks. With genetics out of the way, it is possible to determine clear patterns associated with long lives analyzing Blue Zones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding their diet, they consume an unusual amount of whole plant foods. Although most groups are not strictly vegetarians, they eat meat or fish around five times a month. This fact concurs with a study done on over half a million people, which states that avoiding meat can significantly reduce the risk of death from heart disease, cancer and other common illnesses. At the same time, vegetables, legumes, whole grains and nuts are packed with fiber, vitamins, minerals and omega-3 fats. They also restrict their calories. Okinawans, for instance, follow the “Hara Hachi Bu”, which is also called “The 80% Rule”. As its name indicates, it means stopping to eat when you feel 80% full instead of the usual 100%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about alcohol? There is a surprising amount of papers trying to prove that alcohol is good for your body. It is not. A serious study on red wine concluded that one or two glasses per day may be beneficial because… you guessed it! Not the alcohol. It is actually the grapes’ antioxidants. Nonetheless, people from the Mediterranean Blue Zones drink red wine (in moderation) and their longevity is no joke. This could be linked to their lifestyle. Enjoying a glass of wine with your loved ones could contribute to general happiness and increase life-expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exercise is built in their daily lives. Sardinian men go through long stairs and climb up steep hills as their gym replacement. Not because they choose to, but because they must. There is no skipping leg day when raising farm animals. It is not unusual to get proper sleep when the body is exhausted, which is fantastic because it prevents heart diseases and strokes. They also do daytime naps or “siesta”, seldom longer than half an hour. We Mediterranean people know more than any other the wonders of a good nap… it is not laziness, okay?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a nutshell: if you want to increase your chances for a long and healthy life you should eat properly and in moderation, sleep well, exercise and not drink too much alcohol. It turns out that the Fountain of Youth is astonishingly similar to your mother’s advice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/blue_zones.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fountain of Youth&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Fountain of Youth - ©️ Roisin Callaghan&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math Typesetting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/english/post/math-typesetting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/english/post/math-typesetting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mathematical notation in a Hugo project can be enabled by using third party JavaScript libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example we will be using &lt;a href=&#34;https://katex.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;KaTeX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a partial under &lt;code&gt;/layouts/partials/math.html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Within this partial reference the &lt;a href=&#34;https://katex.org/docs/autorender.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Auto-render Extension&lt;/a&gt; or host these scripts locally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include the partial in your templates like so:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; or .Params.math .Site.Params.math &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt; partial &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;math.html&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; . &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;{{&lt;/span&gt; end &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To enable KaTex globally set the parameter &lt;code&gt;math&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt; in a project&amp;rsquo;s configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To enable KaTex on a per page basis include the parameter &lt;code&gt;math: true&lt;/code&gt; in content files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Use the online reference of &lt;a href=&#34;https://katex.org/docs/supported.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Supported TeX Functions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;examples&#34;&gt;Examples&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline math: \(\varphi = \dfrac{1+\sqrt5}{2}= 1.6180339887…\)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
\varphi = 1+\frac{1} {1+\frac{1} {1+\frac{1} {1+\cdots} } }
$$&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
